

Full Stack Developer

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I have recently entered the world of full stack web development after having completed an intensive 9-week Ruby on Rails course at Le Wagon code school.

Prior to this, I had five years experience in the Information Technology sector working as a Storage Engineer, AWS Certified Solutions Architect and Systems Administrator.

Having worked in high-pressure media environments, I was frequently in situations where I had to think on my feet and troubleshoot.

I have worked in teams of varying sizes and skill sets but also had to use my initiative to work independently when needed.

I enjoy the opportunity to work outside of my comfort zone to expand on industry knowledge, learning new skills and technologies.

EDUCATION & TRAINING

Le Wagon Code School (2018)

Full-Stack Web Development (9-week intensive)

Amazon Web Services (2017)

AWS Certified Solutions Architect

(Associate Level)

Hewlett Packard Education Services (2016)

HK902S Managing HPE 3PAR StoreServ I

HK904S Managing HPE 3PAR StoreServ II

H9P97S Managing HPE 3PAR StoreServ III

The University of Reading (2003 - 2006)

BSc (hons), Computer Science & Cybernetics

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

I volunteer as a mentor at Coder Brixton, a coding youth club for young people of all backgrounds who live in and around the South London area. I am also an avid gamer and enjoy live music.

GET IN TOUCH

- **+**44 (0) 7542 958 966
- # http://kaif.me
- in http://linkedin.com/in/kaifahmed
- https://github.com/brotherkaif

(references available on request)

DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE

⇒ Le Wagon Coding Bootcamp

iii London | October 2018 - Present

Intensive 9 week coding bootcamp learning Ruby on Rails, HTML5, CSS/SCSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, SQL, PostgreSQL, MVC architecture, OOP, git, GitHub, and Heroku.

RECENT PROJECTS

Jammer

http://jammer.rocks

https://github.com/joshbolland/jammer

A networking site designed to help connect budding musicians. Built with Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3/SCSS, Bootstrap and PostgreSQL. Utilises MVC architecture, OOP, git, GitHub, and Heroku.

Musessions

http://musessions.herokuapp.com

https://github.com/joshbolland/musessions

A directory site for discovering and booking session musicians. Built with Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3/SCSS, Bootstrap and PostgreSQL. Utilises MVC architecture, OOP, git, GitHub, and Heroku.

Cocktail Bootleggers

http://cocktail-bootleggers.herokuapp.com

https://github.com/brotherkaif/rails-mister-cocktail

A site that allows the user to create and edit cocktail recipes. Built with Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3 and PostgreSQL. Utilises MVC architecture, OOP and Heroku.

Personal Homepage

http://kaif.me

https://github.com/brotherkaif/brotherkaif.github.io

A fully responsive site intended to showcase my work and develop my frontend skillset. Built with HTML5, CSS3 and hosted on GitHub Pages.

SPECIALIST SKILLS

Development Stack

Ruby on Rails, HTML5, CSS/SCSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, SQL, PostgreSQL, MVC architecture, OOP, Git, GitHub and Heroku.

Cloud Platforms

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate (6 mos).

Storage

HP 3PAR (2 yrs), Brocade SAN switches (2 yrs), SSMC (2 yrs).

Scripting Languages & Tools

BASH (4 yrs), Vim (3 yrs), Atom (6 mos), Visual Studio Code (6 mos), Git (1 yr).

Operating Systems

Linux (3 yrs), macOS (6 yrs), Windows (3 yrs).

A Network Services

SSH (4 yrs), DNS/BIND (2 yrs), NFS (2 yrs), Samba (2 yrs), DHCP (2 yrs), FTP (11 yrs).

♥ Deployment/Management Systems

Casper Suite (1 yr), LANrev (1 yr).

■ Video Production Workflows

Extensive knowledge of video production processes and workflows.

Media Production Suites

Adobe CC Suite (5 yrs).

WORK EXPERIENCE

eg+ Worldwide Technology Support Engineer

🛗 Jun 2018 - Sep 2018 (4 mos) | London, United Kingdom

Omnicom Advanced Services Engineer

苗 Apr 2017 - May 2018 (1 yr 2 mos) | London, United Kingdom

Consolidated Data Services Junior Storage Support Engineer

Feb 2016 - Apr 2017 (1 yr 3 mos) | London, United Kingdom

Consolidated Data Services IT Support Analyst

菌 Jan 2015 - Feb 2016 (1 yr 2 mos) | London, United Kingdom

Hogarth Worldwide Production Engineer

🗰 2014 - Nov 2014 (10 mos) | Cape Town, South Africa

Ogilvy & Mather South Africa Video Editor & Assistant Cameraman

菌 Sep 2012 - Feb 2014 (1 yr 6 mos) | Cape Town, South Africa